It has nothing to do with your Gods.
You face is ugly and your breath stinks.
"When time and moment gather,
two sides will be as one.
"When two shadows come together,
"life will unfurl and death will be done."
The sea is choppy tonight, Admiral.
We are approaching the straits.
It will be calmer then.
Welcome home, Merong.
"Even the vicious tiger
does not eat its cubs"
Merong? Your name is not unknown to us.
We believe we have heard of you.
Ah, no.
Or maybe it was your kin.
I know of a Merong who caused
some trouble in one of our ports.
I heard he went
after a Chinese noblewoman.
That is someone else.
I never went to China.
Too far from my home.
Must be my uncle, Merong Mahasuasa.
Look at him, don't play with him.
You don't belong here, you white ghost.
That boy brings bad luck.
Hey kid! Go away!
This is all your fault.
Why are you crying, Merong?
Boys don't cry easily.
I don't like girls. I hate them.
Am I not a girl?
Listen to me.
When time and moment gather,
two sides will be as one.
When two shadows come together,
life will unfurl and death will be done.
When time and moment gather,
two sides will be as one.
When two shadows come together,
life will unfurl and death will be done.
Come here.
Stay here and be quiet.
Hide here until I come back.
He is the one.
How sure are you?
My feelings say so.
He's the one we've been waiting for.
Where am I?
Do not try to move
lest the wound opens again.
Who... Who are you?
I am Kesum. Shaman of the tribe.
This is my adopted daughter, Embok.
Why?
Rest for a while.
I will take care of you until
you are strong enough.
Don't worry.
The ring will only be opened
when the moon is completely gone.
The ring?
What do they call you?
My name is not fit to be uttered
from the lips of dogs!
How rude!
Did they not teach you manners
and how to respect a man?
You animal! Get off the Princess!
Kamawas, restrain yourself!
Taji, what is the use
of capturing this fine prize
if only to ornament our huts?
Patience, my student.
This is the princess of a great king,
the emperor of China.
A great and strong empire.
And what would insult
the Chinese emperor more
than his daughter
becoming my plaything and my pet?
I have sent a messenger to China.
The princess will not be harmed.
And if the Chinese emperor wishes
for her to continue to be unharmed,
Geruda will be given
a thousand taels of gold
within two full moons.
- A thousand taels of gold?
- Yes!
And if you can find another port
to satisfy your lust for a moon or two,
I am also asking the Chinese emperor
to bow down to Geruda
so we can be kings of these waters!
Many thanks for taking care of me
until I am well.
Are you rushing off somewhere?
Your wounds still bleed, young man.
Have to get the Jentayu... my vessel.
A Jentayu with broken wings will not fly away.
Rest here for a while.
The Prince under my care is gone.
Maybe lost at sea,
or eaten raw by the Gerudans.
What use am I
if I can't fulfil a simple task?
Not only am I a vagabond
chased from port to port,
I also lost my ship.
And with the prince under my watch!
I am useless!
Why am I still alive?
If you'd like,
you can make our village your home.
We come from the earth,
live by water,
but some of our tools...
we craft from the sky.
This keris...
I crafted from star metal.
Keris for a king.
She does not trust outsiders.
Her parents were killed by Gerudans.
Why did you save me?
Why are you so brash?
When will you leave?
When the moon is full?
Pak Kesum believes in you.
He says you are a foreign King.
The saviour of the tribe.
I think you have mistaken me
for someone else.
Our tribe, we are not as one.
We fight each other, and are not united.
The chief of each village
wants to be king.
Pak Kesum stayed where the water falls
for seven days and seven nights
until he dreamt of a prophecy,
but you are not the one.
You are the same
as the rest of the outsiders!
When your wound is healed
you will disappear!
Coward.
Coward?
What prophecy are you talking about?
I don't know any of this.
Yes, I admit.
When my wound is healed
I will be gone.
The matters of the people
are not my concern.
Just get me to a ship.
You want to leave?
Why don't you leave now?
Go. Go!
Leave now!
Pak Kesum?
Yes?
Why is there a scar on Embok's neck?
A scar?
We are a scarred people.
But if it is merely a scar on the body,
then many other tribes
have that as well.
But the scar on her heart...
That scar is shared by many in the tribe.
What do you mean?
Let it be known to you
that the Gerudans came from here.
They used to be part of us.
And Taji, the leader of the Gerudans,
studied under the same master as I.
Let it be known to you that Taji
was also a drifter like yourself.
He was cared for in this very hut.
My master's hut.
Taji's master as well.
He is invulnerable,
because of the amulet around his neck.
Taji begged for the amulet,
so he could become the tribe's shaman.
But my master declined,
because it is his nature
not to give to one who asks for it.
So he stole it and killed my master.
He gathered followers,
many of them the sons of this tribe.
One night, with those loyal to him,
Taji started raiding the villages.
We were surprised, and disorganised.
There were those who fought back.
One of them was Lang,
the Daughter of the previous two chiefs.
She was the first
to get the people to fight back.
The first attack was foiled
by her spirit alone.
But Taji's amulet was too powerful.
Lang?
That is my mother's name.
Then maybe our meeting
was destined after all, young man.
Since then,
the Gerudan pirates would come
every few moons
to take anything their hearts desired.
And once they came,
Kamawas, Taji's student, saw Embok,
the daughter of the chief.
Her father and I tried to stop him.
But Kamawas was also invulnerable
to dagger and spear.
That is why, we are all scarred.
Disunited.
So how do we destroy Geruda?
What did you see in the prophecy?
Prophecy?
Embok told you?
Yes, seven days and seven nights
under falling water.
What vision appeared to you?
I had a dream on the seventh night
that a foreign king would come
in the heat of battle.
He will be the one to unite the tribe.
I believe...
You are the one whose coming was foretold.
I think the prophecy is mistaken.
Or... I am the wrong man.
I am not a foreigner.
I remember...
I used to lived here.
When time and moment gather,
two sides will be as one
What did you say?
The pantoum.
It's mother's pantoum.
Where did you hear it?
The prophecy came with the pantoum.
This is the pantoum.
Two warring villages
will be as one and fight Geruda.
If you still wish to go...
we will not hold you back.
Great teacher Kesum, guide me.
What am I to do?
Prepare the roof properly.
This will be our shelter
if the Gerudans come again.
- How's our progress?
- It will be ready in a couple of days.
In the meantime,
this will be our resting place.
Pak Kesum,
there are outsiders on our shore.
Kamawas, we are to be attacked!
How can that be?
By whom?
The mainlanders.
The two villages unite under a new king.
Kesum's damned prophecy has come true.
The villagers?
How can the few defeat the many?
They are only a few hundred,
most of them farmers.
We number in the thousands ofwarriors.
My séance shows
that ifwe overcome this obstacle,
these waters will be ours.
What are you talking about?
Fall, and we shall never rise again.
Are you trying to scare me?
They are not to land on our shores.
I will not sail in the dead of night.
And leave you alone with the Princess.
That's your plan, isn't it?
Kamawas! Don't forget!
Your invulnerability is all due to my amulet!
Lose it, and you will bleed like the rest!
Don't you ever forget it!
Wake me up if they reach our shores.
You're going senile.
Go attack them, Kamawas!
Where do you think you're going?
As long as Taji draws breath,
how can I show my face here?
Pak Kesum, you stay here.
Take care of Embok.
Take care of the rest.
You have done enough.
Embok.
We might not come back.
If that happens, please take care.
We should not stand here for long.
Go.
Go forth and avenge your mother.
And avenge yourself as well.
- Let us say our good...
- Don't!
This keris you carry,
it will weaken Taji's magic.
But it will not take away his invulnerability.
His and Kamawas' invulnerability
lies in the amulet.
Take away their amulets
and you can take their lives.
I will not forget your advice.
Thank you for everything, Pak Kesum.
Be wary of Geruda's arrows!
If you get wounded,
we have the salve to heal it here.
Goodbye, Embok!
Take care of yourself!
No! Our King will take care of us!
Our King...
will surely come back!
Good evening, sweet one.
You are not yet asleep?
And why are you here?
Shouldn't you be with your men?
My men should be fine.
Men do not smell as nice as women.
And who dares to breach
the impenetrable fortress of Geruda?
So what is the reason
for this late night visit?
lfwe don't receive news
from China tomorrow you will be mine.
I have waited long enough.
I want to have a peek ofwhat is to be mine.
The moon is almost full tonight.
Does it not make you feel
like walking by the shore
and enjoying the beauty of the night?
I would rather sit here
and drink in your beauty.
Then, I see no harm in that.
Let us lie awhile and compose poetry.
Poetry?
Can't you stem your impulse?
I have a headache.
Come tomorrow night
after I have recovered my vigour.
I cannot hold it in much longer.
You will be mine tonight.
People of Langkasuka.
Men of the tribes. Hear me out.
For many moons Geruda's talons
have scratched and wounded us,
scarred our hearts
and taken those who are dear to us.
And though I am your King,
but for today I will fight as one of you.
The blood that flows within us
is the same colour.
With the same thickness.
We breathe the same air.
Walk on the same ground
covered by the same sky.
It is for our children that we do this.
Today...
Some of us may not return.
Maybe many, maybe all of us will die.
But what's the point of living
ifwe are not free
from the brutality that is Geruda?
How long do we allow our sons and daughters
be fed to those monsters?
Yes.
We fight to take back
this young Prince's bride.
But that is not all.
We will also take back our honour.
Our dignity, as the people of Langkasuka
does not lie within your King.
It lies within our land that we protect.
I would rather die than live as a slave.
A slave to the terror
and violence of those animals!
In the name of our pride
and the sovereignty of our kingdom,
Let us reap the field of Gerudans!
Attack!
Have Geruda's wings been clipped?
I will break every single bone in your body.
I am scared to the bone.
Rescue the princess!
Kill the pirates!
This is for Embok's scar.
You bastard!
May your scars never stop bleeding,
even after you die.
The pleasure of Embok I still feel now.
Drop your weapons or your leader dies.
When time and moment gather,
two sides will be as one.
When two shadows come together,
life will unfurl and death will be done.